The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Thirty-Seventh Episode
The Magic Tree
Ladies and gentlemen,
today we present to you...
...the second part
of "Mephisto's Spell"
We remind you what happened
in the first part,
presented
in the previous episode.
Hell, Hecate's mother,
turns Sapphire into a doll,
commanding her to go
towards Mephisto's cave.
Meanwhile Hecate, who refused
to become a witch,
runs away from home.
On the road she meets Sapphire.
...and takes her
to the kingdom of Goldland,
where Prince Franz lives,
Sapphire's best friend.
The Prince,
willing to give refuge to Sapphire,
notices that the girl
he is infatuated with...
...is, in reality, Sapphire herself
and decides to protect her from Mephisto.
But the evil Hell tracks down
Sapphire at Goldland castle...
...and, to take her back, turns
the inhabitants of the castle into stone.
The Prince fights with Hell
and with Mephisto, risking his life,
but Hell defeats him
and takes Sapphire away.
Sapphire!
Poor Franz...!
Don't be so sad,
Prince Franz!
Kitty, you speak! Don't fear, I
won't reveal your secret to anyone.
- You understand my pain, don't you?
- Yes, I understand it.
Oh, if only I could have
my Sapphire back!
Sapphire! Sapphire! Sapphire!
Sapphire!
Damned Mephisto,
don't be so cruel!
Give me back my Sapphire! I offer
you my life in exchange for hers!
Prince Franz,
I know where Sapphire is.
What? You know where she is? Tell me!
I don't know if I'm doing
the right thing by telling you.
But you must tell me! Please,
tell me right now where she is! Please!
Wait a moment,
I'm going to check!
Oh, what should I do?!
Mom and Dad must have
certainly taken her to the cave!
What would they say if I brought
Prince Franz down there?
I don't care if they scold me,
but they might treat him badly...
.and I really don't like that!
Oh, what a huge problem! But I have to
solve it one way or another.
So, kitty, did you check?
Did you see which direction
they took? Quick, tell me!
Yes, I saw that they went
that way.
Here I am, Sapphire! I'm coming!
What a situation I've gotten myself into!
How will it end?
Prince Franz,
all I can do is trust in you.
Oh, I'm so annoyed!
Where has Hecate gone?
Try consulting
your crystal ball.
We're reduced to consulting
the crystal ball...
..to know where our daughter is,
who goes out without even
telling her parents!
Here are the consequences of
the upbringing that you gave her!
Don't be so shrewish, my dear!
Maybe she isn't coming back precisely so
she doesn't have to hear your grumbling!
Shut up! Don't talk nonsense!
And look: the crystal
ball is blackened!
You're so lazy that you don't
even take care of your things!
Now clean it, if you
want to use it! Go on!
Today I feel depressed! Who
wouldn't be with a wife like that?
Stop complaining, you
lazybones! And keep polishing!
Franz won't be able to find me.
When Hecate returns home,
Mephisto will not waste time...
...and will immediately
exchange my heart with hers.
I must escape before she returns.
How strange... I feel like I've
already passed through here.
Are you making me go in circles, kitty?
Tell the truth: do you really
know where Sapphire is?
- Yes, I know!
- Then tell me exactly where she is.
Well, look, she should
be... She's over there!
You say she's locked in
that house? Let's go see!
Sapphire!
Sapphire, where are
you? It is I: Prince Franz!
Perhaps it's Mephisto who's
preventing her from answering.
I'll find her anyway!
Maybe she's here! Or here!
Forgive me, Franz.
You told me a lie, kitty.
Sapphire is not in this house!
Forgive me, Franz, I didn't
mean to deceive you! I'm not a liar!
It's just that I felt so
sorry for you, so I...
Ah, well! Finally you have revealed
yourself for what you are, kitty!
- You're an agent of Mephisto, right?
- Oh, no!
Mephisto, don't mock me!
Take my life
in exchange for Sapphire's!
I would like to help him, but
how can I do it? I have an idea!
Hail Mephisto!
- Show yourself, Mephisto! Show yourself!
- Prince Franz!
Sapphire, is it you?
Yes, Franz! I
managed to escape!
Oh, Sapphire! How
happy I am to see you!
How wicked I am...
I am deceiving him!
But how I wish he would
see me as Sapphire!
Sapphire, why is there
that tear on your face?
Wait! Don't go away!
Sapphire, what is happening
to you? Wait for me!
Forgive me, Prince
Franz, I beg you!
I am not Sapphire! In reality, I
am Hecate, the daughter of Mephisto!
It was always me,
even that little kitten.
If you are really the daughter of
Mephisto, what do you want from me?
You were so sad that
I tried to comfort you...
by taking on the appearance of
Sapphire. I beg you, Prince, forgive me!
Forgive you?! How can I forgive
you? You were only mocking me!
Only a diabolical soul
could devise such a trick!
Oh, no! How I wish I
wasn't the daughter of Mephisto!
There, now it’s nice and shiny!
- Look how marvelous, dear!
- Let me see!
- Sapphire has escaped!
- What are you saying?!
Damn! She escaped while I was polishing the sphere!
You're a real idiot!
One more effort...
You can't escape! Now I'll catch you again and take you back to your cell!
- And make sure you don't escape again!
- No!
Well then, Sapphire!
You wanted to escape, eh?
Hail Mephisto!
This way she won't escape!
Leave me alone! You bastard!
- You bastard!
- It's no use resisting!
No!
Dammit!
I'll have to polish it again!
Hecate!
I'm sorry for what I said.
Now I understand that, after all,
you wanted to help me.
You disguised yourself as Sapphire with good
intentions, to bring me comfort.
Prince, I believe there is
only one way to save her.
Really? And what would it be?
I know that it was
my parents who kidnapped her,
so she must be
locked up in our house.
Then tell me:
where is your house located?
No, wait!
No matter how strong you are,
you can never hope
to surpass my parents!
- But...
- But?
If you blinded them,
you might succeed.
What? Blind your parents?!
But only for a short time.
At the top of the Mountain of Ghosts
there is a tree:
they say its sap makes
anyone who drinks it lose their sight.
The Mountain of Ghosts?
What's the matter, Hecate?
Hail Mephisto!
Kitty! Oop-la!
Why have you transformed yourself, Hecate?
Mom and Dad are looking for me
with the magic sphere,
so I created a double of myself
to escape them.
I'll make her walk through the woods,
so they'll think I'm still here.
Little sister, walk while singing!
There is a Prince I love
and he doesn't know it yet...
But it's Hecate!
Darling, I found where Hecate is!
Damn, they found her!
Then it's over for me!
She's in the woods, at the foot
of Ghost Mountain
What are you waiting for?!
Move, go there immediately!
Alright, alright! I'm running!
And don't come back if you
haven't found her, damn the devil!
Excuse me, usually
I'm not so vulgar!
The Prince is far away, he
doesn't realize that I love him.
- The Prince is far away...
- Hecate!
Why did you go away! Your
mother is furious, you know? Now...
But then it was just an image!
Hecate! Can I know
where you've gotten to?
Here is the tree
of the evil spirit!
My mother told me that
whoever touches it is cursed.
But there's nothing else
to be done, unfortunately!
Stay here, Prince
Franz! I will go on alone.
Be careful, Hecate!
Hail Mephisto!
You are in danger, Hecate!
Go back!
The evil spirit is angry,
but I must do it anyway!
Damn it, take this!
Quick, Hecate, come
back here! It will hurt you!
There!
You did it!
This sap is enough
for what I have in mind.
Now we must go back.
- Hecate, what's wrong?
- I feel terrible!
I have the evil spirit's curse
upon me!
Hecate, you knew about the curse
and you wanted to go anyway.
Now don't worry about me!
If my parents find you, you won't
be able to save Sapphire anymore!
We must hurry,
so follow me!
Hecate!
Now, Franz,
don't move from there...
...until I give you a signal.
- All right.
Where on earth could Hecate have gone?
I'm so worried about her!
- Papa!
- Hecate!
You're finally back home!
My little girl!
Darling, Hecate is here! She's back!
Finally, some good news!
Hecate, my child! Where have you
been? We've been so worried about you!
Don't scold her, dear! Ever since
she returned, she seems very unwell!
She's unwell? She has a guilty conscience
for having made us suffer so much!
But now we will perform
the operation immediately...
...to swap her heart with Sapphire's.
- Isn't it better to wait?
- No!
If the operation must be done,
it's better that it's done right away.
Hail Mephisto!
Good, now have Sapphire brought here!
- Help! Help, Franz! Help!
- But that's Sapphire's voice!
Franz, help me!
Hold on, Sapphire! I have
to wait for Hecate's signal.
What are you waiting for, my
daughter? Lie down here, next to Sapphire.
Has the moment arrived when
I will become a great witch?
Of course, my daughter!
Even if you're feeling sick, don't worry.
Afterward, you'll be able
to recover from any illness.
I think I'll become much
more capable than I am now.
- Do you want to toast to this?
- Certainly, Hecate!
Hail Mephisto!
I don't feel well...
Mother, can I ask you a favor?
Tell me what you want, little one,
and don't worry.
Soon you will feel much better.
I've heard that decent people
never fail to make a toast
when they are about to celebrate
something.
"Decent people"?! You want me
to make a toast? But of course!
Give me a glass, dear!
- To the birth of a
great witch! - Cheers!
Forgive me, mother and father...
What's happening?
I can hardly see anymore!
Franz, come here! Franz!
Hecate, why on earth are you calling Franz?!
Where are you, Hecate?
What the hell are you doing?
- Franz! - There's the signal!
Hecate is calling me!
- Franz, hurry up!
- What's happening?
Could Prince Franz have come
to take Sapphire back?!
- Dammit, I can't see anything!
- Sapphire! Sapphire, wake up!
Hurry up! Escape, quickly!
Hecate, you saved me! I will
be forever grateful to you!
Hecate, you dared to betray
your parents?!
I have already received
punishment from the evil spirit.
- What?!
- Yes, perhaps I will die for this.
Flee with us, Hecate! I can't
bear the thought of you dying!
What do I hear! Hecate is
dying?! No, for heaven's sake! No!
Quick, Sapphire, let's take her away!
Stop! I won't let you escape!
If only I could see
where they are! Damn it!
Devil of a woman! She
hit me instead of them!
We must try to get through
at all costs, Sapphire!
Run, Sapphire!
Follow me or they'll catch us!
I'm following you, Franz!
Catch them! Catch them!
Damn you!
Get out of the way!
- Hecate!
- My daughter!
Courage, Hecate!
Lord, save my friend Hecate,
even if she is the daughter of Mephisto!
Even if she is the daughter of the devil,
her soul is purer
than any other.
Free her from the curse!
Look, Hecate is opening her eyes!
Praise be to God! You're safe, Hecate!
What are you saying? God?! But I'm in a church!
Let me out, quick,
otherwise I'll die!
Don't forget that I am
the daughter of Mephisto!
But Hecate, we brought you here
to make you heal!
Far from dying! It's here, in
church, that you have come back to life!
God saved you because, although
the daughter of Mephisto, you have a pure soul.
The Lord has freed you from the
curse of the evil spirit!
It's strange that Mephisto's
daughter is being helped by God...
..and in a church, no
less! Don't you think?
Hecate, actually
you're an angel to us!
Hecate!
Mom and Dad are looking for me!
- Hecate!
Hecate!
Hecate, we beg you!
Come home!
We got our sight back!
Don't worry!
We apologized to the evil
spirit and to the Great Devil!
- Everything is fine now!
- We won't be mean to you anymore!
Please, come home!
- Hecate!
Mom and Dad worry about me
- Do you want to return, Hecate?
- Thank you so much, Hecate.
Hail Mephisto!
Goodbye, friends!
Goodbye, Hecate! Goodbye!
- Sapphire.
- Yes, Franz?
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP